<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Josh Mashes Keys]]></title>
  <link href="http://idlemouse.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://idlemouse.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-08-30T00:54:37+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://idlemouse.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[J.D. Foster]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Got Distracted -- Ooooh Shiny!]]></title>
    <link href="http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/08/29/i-got-distracted/"/>
    <updated>2015-08-29T23:27:48+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/08/29/i-got-distracted</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been quite a while and my plans went awry from that I had
planned. Time to start again&hellip; As I had mentioned before I am using
<strong>octopress</strong>, which works a treat most of the time. There are a few
novel quirks that it could do without. Hopefully the release of
octopress 3 will sort these out. I had been putting off posting and
waiting for the to the official release and hence the delay. Today I
spent a few hours trying to migrating over my current blog with theme
layout to latest version, but hit a few brick walls and am thinking to
now wait till some kind souls creates some interesting new themes.</p>

<p>A list of post I would like to write:</p>

<ul>
<li>Finish albums from last year post</li>
<li>Write a entry on current my emacs GNUS/BBDB/MSTP setup</li>
<li>Menu item to list publication</li>
<li>Upload some of my <strong>R</strong> functions</li>
<li>SQLite recursive functions and frustration of LinuxMint</li>
<li>Play around with <strong>d3</strong> some of my published data</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tippity Top Albums 2014 (Pt1)]]></title>
    <link href="http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/02/16/tippity-top-albums-2014-pt1/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-16T22:40:06+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/02/16/tippity-top-albums-2014-pt1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Beck - <em>Morning Phase</em></h3>

<p><em>I like cake and I like this album</em></p>

<p>Like a beautiful crafted piece of chocolate cake. You think you can
just listen to a single track, but soon you are under the spell of its
allure and quickly fall into a whole chocolate gorging session with
spoon doesn&rsquo;t seem to delivery large enough dollops of gooey
goodness. In essence, more stripped back than previous albums with
electronic sounds being replaced by strings. Leaving a almost operatic
sounding album. More overtly darker in content than Beck&rsquo;s previous
albums, but no less self indulgent. For me it is a gem, with Wave as
it beating heart, recalling memories of Radiohead&rsquo;s Pyramid Song, in
my book that is not a bad thing. A pleasure I could quiet happy enjoy
in repetition without any guilt.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/m2DLZkv4Yvg" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>Cold Specks - <em>Neuroplasticity</em></h3>

<p><em>Refined Dark Gospel</em></p>

<p>Girlfriends past have accused me of being a music snob! Taking some
kind of giddy pleasure in listening to music of <em>obscure</em> bands and
judging other from my tower of records. Lies, scandalous lies, I say!
In light of such slanderous accusations against my music scruples. I
would like it to be known that I want people to know this album, it
needs to be heard. Darkly brooding, menacing reflection of the
undulating path one takes through life. It has feel of a finely
filtered blend of gospel, jazz and 60s psychedelia. With each listen
it has surprised me with the amount of raw passion that is exposed.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/yKSNUHBwfPM" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<h3>Mogwai - <em>RAVE TAPES</em></h3>

<p><em>Les Revenants</em></p>

<p>Prior to releasing this album, Mogwai composed an amazing soundtrack
for the french TV series Les Revenants (The Returned). This album is
most definitely a very different beast. The former offers us a
orchestral delight, whereas this album displays the dexterity and
versatility that electronic music can offer. Taken together these two
albums portrays just how talented a band they are. The spectrum and
deliverance in RAVE TAPES is both board and sweeping. It has a feel of
music which they have taken a great pleasure in making and turning it
into a record as a after thought. Release towards the beginning of the
year I had planned to see them preform in Glasgow, but alas had to
sell my tickets as I had a job interview. 2014 the year I could have
seen Mogwai live in Glasgow, but instead got a new job. While this is
a detour from the like of past heights such as <em>Come On Die Young</em> I
still fell it is a noteworthy album of the year.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sZ5nEuG-CRc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[For Some Time Now]]></title>
    <link href="http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/01/26/for-some-time-now/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-26T23:08:55+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/01/26/for-some-time-now</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been using GNU/Linux on-and-off for quiet some time now. My
first experience was using PPC editions of SuSE on my iBook back in
the early 2000s and later Mandrake on my beat-up PC. But I never
really got into using for my default go-to operating system. Plus
coming from a DOS background made using UNIX a little bewildering. A
lot has changed since then.</p>

<p>I have had dual-boot Linux/Windows systems for a long time now, but it
has only been more recently that I switch to using GNU/Linux as my
day-to-day system. <em>With the exception of a month where I switch to
solely using linux while I was writing a chapter of my PhD thesis,
however I found I was using a Windows virtual machine far too much and
switched back.</em> One of the main reasons for my conversion to
GNU/Linux, this time around, was the implantation of statistical
programming language <strong>R</strong> during my first post-doc job at the University
of St Andrews. The many aim was to make circular plots and circular
statistics, without having to use a clunky third-party plugin for
Excel. But the ability to identically batch process data and making
beautiful graphics really sold it for me. However, since then I have
been more included to use MATLAB, although not perfect, it is a more
complete solution and allows for user-interfaces.</p>

<p>At present, I am using a mix between Xubuntu (on my home desktop),
Linux-Mint (office desktop) and Arch-Linux (laptop/chromebook), all
using the sleek xfce graphical environment. Arch-Linux has been my
most recent discovery, although not for the faint hearted or the UNIX
reluctant, it is my current distribution of choice. When first
installed it is just a bare-bone terminal, from which to build on to
get to a complete usable system. It can, and did for me, take a entire
weekends work to get an installed and fully functional system. Which
has really force me to delve into UNIX/Linux to a much greater extent
that I would have done otherwise. But it has provided me a neat system
with just the elements, and that suits me just fine. Plus it is
something that you have lovely crafted and customised which only add
to it charm.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Stumbling Out of the Starting Gate]]></title>
    <link href="http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/01/19/stumbling-out-of-the-starting-gate/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-19T22:38:40+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/01/19/stumbling-out-of-the-starting-gate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Second post of the year and I am already behind my goal of one post a week. Which is unfortunate, but hopefully things will pick up again from here on out. I have a few ideas for the some future posts which I am looking forward to writing. It is just a matter of fixing a time to sit down and just write them.</p>

<p>I thought that I would keep things a bit simple for the second post and explain about my choice of blogging site. But first a story of days long past when I was at university and before the social media sites of today. In those bygone days we relied on MySpace (good purchase J.T.), which was a bit meh and too public. So in attempted to make something different I created a website (hacking together a bulletin-board and photo-hosting mess) which kinda worked. The plan was for it to be used for a small groups of friends to post-photos and messages in a closed community. Yes it was super fun to make, but it was a pain to maintain and difficult to add any additional functionality. Plus in the time when SMS and MSN messenger were king it was under used&hellip; time pasted and I didn&rsquo;t renew the hosting or keep the URL address or a backup of photos or messages (a shame).</p>

<p>Granted, it would be possible to hash something together and self-host a site on a micro-server at home without too much trouble. But alas creating and maintaining a site plus server has been such a time-vortex in the past that I fear it would detract for my other plans. Alternatively, I could use one of the many blogging sites for hosting my tiny blog, but I feel that they lack a bit of customisation (and soul).</p>

<p>Thus the current iteration of my blog is being hosting by <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a>, which I feel is a happy alternative. Providing simplicity for hosting and full control of content. I am pretty happy so far. For the site I am using <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> for the main skeleton with the <a href="https://github.com/johnkeith/boldandblue">Bold-and-Blue</a> theme. Octopress utilises <a href="http://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> for fleshing out the pages themselves. Jekyll is a great program, which used converts the beautifully simplistic <a href="https://github.com/adam-p/markdown-here/wiki/Markdown-Cheatsheet">markdown language</a> into tasty HTML code. Using this setup has the added advantage of use of static pages and thus avoid the headache of using databases to maintain content. Easy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Educated Fool]]></title>
    <link href="http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/01/02/an-educated-fool/"/>
    <updated>2015-01-02T16:31:47+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://idlemouse.github.io/blog/2015/01/02/an-educated-fool</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the beginning of a project that I have had in mind for some
time, which I have now finally had the time commit to get it up and
running. For this endeavour I am hoping to write a blog fit for others
to read (well hopefully).</p>

<p>My plan is to write and post a blog on a <del>weekly basis for the next
year</del> semi-regular basis. Although this posting frequency may vary
slightly depending on how eventful life becomes and my time allows. I
don&rsquo;t have any particular target audience nor a reason to blog other
that for enjoyment. That is not to say that this won&rsquo;t evolve and
start to follow a pattern.</p>

<p>Obviously, it goes without say that my writing is my own opinion and
probably won&rsquo;t be reviewed, therefore should be taken with a pinch of
salt (as most things on the internet). I would like to think there
will be some integrity to may writing, but I might just piss it all
away on some whim.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
